Cory Heslip

10124 Inverness Main St Englewood, CO 80112 (720) 989-6512

PROFILE

Experienced software engineer with a unique background in both computer and life sciences. A self-starter with a demonstrated ability to quickly learn, adapt and utilize a variety of languages and technologies to solve problems and create new user experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Expert in Java and Python, proficient in JavaScript and Objective-C, and well versed C++ and PHP.

Web Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, LESS, jQuery, JSON, REST, AJAX

 $Databases:\ PostgreSQL,\ MySQL,\ SQLite$

Source Control: Git, Perforce

Software: Eclipse, Netbeans, Xcode, PyCharm, Chrome Operating Systems: Mac OS, Linux, Windows, iOS, Android

PROJECTS

Specimen Suitability App: iOS and Android app that aids the organ and tissue donor community in determining the testing suitability of blood specimens. (Obj-C, Java). – Winner of American Association of Tissue Banks Communication, Advertising and Marketing Award.

Specimen Archiver: Web based application to simplify tracking and storing laboratory specimens (PHP, MySQL).

Open Garage: Website for a social networking startup that aims to connect people with others in order to learn a new hobby or skill (Python, Django framework).

See more on GitHub: https://github.com/cheslip/

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (mid-level)

Auguest 2013 - present

Time Warner Cable (contractor), Native Client Navigation, Broomfield, CO

- Made rich user experience possible on legacy set top boxes by improving efficiency of JPEG image loading.
- Implemented remote commands for digital video recorder functionality to support mobile initiative.
- Created a system profiling tool using Python and JavaScript (AngularJS) to discover problem areas in codebase.
- Increased performance of digital video recording for next generation navigation platform in multiple areas by using profiling tool.

 $Software\ Engineering\ Intern$

June 2013 - August 2013

Time Warner Cable, Native Client Navigation, Broomfield, CO

- Designed and implemented in Java a replacement for a legacy configuration management system for set top boxes.
- Utilized JUnit to bring test code coverage of configuration management to 90%

Laboratory Technologist / Mobile App Developer March 2011 - present VRL Laboratories, Infectious Disease Department, Centennial, CO

- Created the VRL Specimen Suitability App for iOS and Android. This app assists clients in determining specimen suitability.
- Improved night shift logistics by creating a Microsoft Outlook script to track incoming specimen shipments.
- Perform ELISA and nucleic acid testing of 40 blood specimens per night on average.

Web Application Developer / Co-Founder

July 2012 - present

Open Garage, currently in development

- Utilized the Django framework and many different web technologies to build a unique new social network from the ground up.
- Created new features by using Python, JavaScript, JQuery and by customizing existing open source projects
- Designed a simple and pleasing user interface using CSS and JavaScript.
- Deployed the current state of the website to testers in order to gain feedback for improvements.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Software Engineering Colorado Technical University, Denver, CO, expected 2014 Current GPA: 3.6

Bachelor of Arts, Biology and Chemistry University of Colorado at Colorado Springs, Colorado Springs, CO, May 2010 Associations: Beta Beta Biological Honor Society